【翻译】巴蛮子sz
Sincro: wyxchari
【时间轴】巴蛮子sz
【校对】巴蛮子sz
基于 opentitles.org 英文字幕翻译
Sincro: wyxchari
命令-已收到. 消灭所有人类!
Orders received. Exterminate all humans!
消灭所有人类!
Exterminate all humans!
终结! 灭绝! 摧毁! Daleks-征服-并摧毁!
Exterminate! Annihilate! Destroy! Daleks conquer and destroy!
Daleks-征服-并摧毁! Daleks-征服-并摧毁! Daleks-征服-并摧毁! ...
Daleks conquer and destroy! Daleks conquer and destroy! ...
占据-地形. 准备-毁灭-所有-人类.
Take up positions. Ready to exterminate all human beings.
终结！
Exterminate!
终结！ 终结！ 终结！ 终结！
Exterminate! Exterminate! Exterminate! Exterminate!
继续走!
Move on!
有 Dalek!
The Dalek!
那怎么了?
What about it?
你看不出来他是有武器的?
Can't you see it's armed?
继续前进!
Keep moving!
这个-区域-已经-禁止.
This area is restricted.
谁授权的?
On whose authority?
安静!
Silence!
重复. 这个-区域-已经-禁止.
Repeat. This area is restricted.
服从-否则-你们-会被-毁灭.
Obey or you shall be exterminated.
我以为是它们服从我们?
I thought they obeyed us?
我们现在怎么办, Doctor?
What do we do now, Doctor?
这边走.
This way.
他们-会被-毁灭.
They will be exterminated.
我们已经赢了. 革命已经结束了. 我将传话给 Valmar, Kebble 和其他人.
We've won. The revolution's over.
I'll pass the word to Valmar, Kebble and the rest.
等等. 革命还没完全结束.
Wait. The revolution is not quite over yet.
我们还要做什么? Hensell 已经死了, 你成了新总督. 战斗也结束了.
What more can we do? Hensell's dead,
you're the new Governor. The battle's over.
不完全. 你提到了 Kebble, Valmar 等一群人. 他们必须要处理掉.
Not quite. You mentioned Kebble, Valmar and that rabble.
Well now they must be dealt with.
但那是我们的人.
But those are our own men.
呵, 呵. 当然.
Huh, huh. Of course.
我不明白.
I don't understand.
如果这群闹事的人放任自流的话, 你觉得我可能是安全的吗?
Do you think I can ever be secure in that chair
while that rabble are still loose?
他们昨天反叛的是 Hensell, 明天就可能轮到我了. 算了, 让他们闹事吧.
They rebelled against Hensell yesterday.
Tomorrow it'll be my turn. Well, let them rebel.
跟他们说保安已经掌握控制权了, 让他们进攻, 然后我们就可以镇压他们, 一举歼灭!
Tell them the guards have taken control.
Let them attack, and then we can crush them, utterly!
你说了＂我们＂.
You say "we".
是的. 我们一路走了这么久, 你和我. 你现在要回那边去吗?
Yes. We've come a long way together you and I.
You going to back down now?
你不能仅仅只是逮捕他们吗?
Couldn't you just arrest them?
所有人必须死.
Everyone must be killed.
他们必须全部都被屠杀掉?
Must they all be slaughtered?
他们全部.
All of them.
哦, 你跟我还是一条心吗?
Well, are you still with me?
我觉得是.
I suppose so.
那就按我说的做. 我很高兴你同意我的意见.
Then do as I say. I'm glad you agreed with me.
现在!
Now!
你把我带来这里做什么?
What have you brought me in here for?
安静!
Quiet!
你到底是属哪边的?
Whose side are you on anyway?
我想我以前属于要得胜的一边.
I thought I was going to be on the winning side.
怎么改变主意了?
What changed your mind?
Bragen. 这个基地对他来说太小了. 他现在不想要任何人挡他的道.
Bragen. The colony's become too small for him.
He wants us out of the way now.
是的, 这种事最后经常是这样, 伙计, 当你跟着他这样的家伙.
Yeah, well it often happens that way, mate,
when you follow blokes like him.
看, 我要去试着把你的朋友们找来, 尽我所能. 你等在这里.
Look, I'm going to try and get your friends here,
if I can. So wait here.
总督 Bragen, 一号区域报告.
Station One reporting, Governor Bragen.
说.
Yes.
叛乱分子正在集结, 我们正在密切注意事态.
The rebels are gathering. We've got them under observation.
别让他们聚集成大的群组. 在他们组织起来前进行打击. 现在他们马上就要有所行动了.
Don't let them concentrate in large groups. Hit them before
they organise.They'll be making their move any time now.
好的.
Right.
Vulcan 人民请注意. 现在是你们的新总督在讲话
People of Vulcan. This is your new Governor talking to you
我不得不告知大家总督 Hensell 已经被叛乱分子谋杀了
I have to announce that Governor Hensell has been murdered by the rebels.
我已经暂时获得了控制权, 直到秩序恢复. 住在卫星城和内城的群众请保持冷静
I have taken control temporarily, until order is restored.
People living on the perimeter and in the interior can stay calm.
我们已经知道凶手是谁. 我一旦获知任何消息, 将尽可能及时知会大家
We know who the murderers are.
I shall keep you informed of events as soon as I am able
所以请留意你们的通讯设备中的信号. 广播结束.
So listen for the signal to watch your communication sets. That is all.
啊! 你在这里啊.
Ah! There you are.
Ben!
我就知道你会没事的!
I knew you'd be all right!
Polly - 你还好吧?
Polly - you okay?
噢, 是的.
Oh, yes.
Valmar 去找你们了, 碰到了吗?
Did Valmar find you, then?
Valmar? 没有.
Valmar? No.
又有 Valmar 什么事?
What's this about Valmar?
是这样, 看起来 Bragen 已经疯狂了. 他故意让叛乱分子起来闹事, 然后他好再把他们消灭掉.
Well it seems Bragen's gone power-mad.
He wants the rebels to revolt, then he can finish them off.
Daleks 不会在乎跟谁打. 他们会毁灭这个星球上的每一个人.
The Daleks won't care who they fight.
They'll exterminate every human being on this planet.
Doctor, 求你了, 我们回到 TARDIS 去吧.
Doctor, please let's go back to the TARDIS.
Quinn. 看住他们俩.
Quinn. Keep them both here.
喂, 等一下, 博士!
Well, wait a minute, Doctor!
好吧, 好吧. All right.
All right. All right.
现在你觉得他要干什么?
Now what do you think he's up to?
命令-已收到. Daleks-开始-终结!
Orders received. Daleks commence extermination.
终结！ 终结！ 终结！
Exterminate! Exterminate! Exterminate!
等一下, 监察员.
Just a minute, Examiner.
好了. 停住!
All right. Hold it!
都趴下!
Down everyone!
别往前走了.
Don't come any nearer.
你什么意思?
What do you mean?
我无意中听到你跟 Bragen 的谈话
I overheard your conversation with Bragen.
但你们是没法站起来对抗 Daleks的, 因此你们的计划将会落空.
But you can't stand up to the Daleks,
so your plan will come to nothing.
不是我的计划 - 是 Bragen 的.
Not my plan - Bragen's.
但那是一回事.
But that's the same thing.
不再是了.
Not any more.
你期望我能相信?
You expect me to believe that?
Val, 他当时也想杀了我的. 我来这里是要做你已经做了的事情.
Look Val, he was going to kill me too.
I came here to do exactly what you've done.
让 Bragen 看看 Daleks 到底是怎样的东西. 他不知道它们有多强悍.
Let Bragen see what the Daleks are like.
He doesn't know how strong they are.
必须得有人阻止他.
He's got to be stopped.
你们-必须-带我们-去到-你们-人类-中间.
You will lead us to the middle of your party of human beings.
是.
Yes.
我们-将-战斗-为你们
We will fight for you.
相信我, Val, 这是救我们命的唯一方法.
Believe me, Val, it's the only way to save all our lives.
你知道那些 Daleks 在自我复制吗?
Did you know that the Daleks are duplicating?
是的.
Yes.
但是-我们-是-你们的-朋友.
But we are your friends.
我们-将要-服务于-你们.
We will serve you.
带-我们-去-你们-小组-中间.
Take us to the centre of your group.
我们能信任他们吗?
Can we trust them?
必须得! 保安们已经收到命令要把我们彻底消灭. 我们必须得利用 Daleks. 快来.
We must! The guards have orders to wipe us out.
We must use the Daleks. Come on.
博士!
Doctor!
这个窗户. 能打开吗?
The window. Does it open?
我不知道.
I dunno.
最好能, 否则我们就完蛋了! 你快出去.
It had better, or we're done for! Out you go.
啊!... 啊!... 发生了什么?
Ah!... Ah!... What's happening?
Daleks. 他们在走廊集结, 都快挤满了. 我们得回到 Lesterson 的实验室去.
The Daleks. They're teeming all over the corridors.
We've got to get back to Lesterson's lab.
现在是总督 Bragen 讲话. 一组叛乱分子试图占领基地
This is Governor Bragen speaking.
A group of rebels is attempting to take over the colony.
所有忠诚的市民有责任帮助保安抵抗他们.
It is the duty of all loyal citizens to help the guards resist.
请待在家里, 等待秩序恢复. 保持关注我的简报.
Stay in your homes. Order will be restored.
Listen to my bulletins.
叛乱分子正在利用 Daleks 反击我们的人!
The rebels are using the Daleks against our people!
那就回去战斗啊! 你跑到我这里来干什么? 你觉得你们的枪是干什么用的?
Well, get back and fight! Why do you come running to me?
What do you think your guns are for?
但是, 枪对它们不管用啊!
Well, the guns don't work against them!
回去, 打他们!
Get back and fight them!
那儿, 那儿!
There, and there!
还有那儿!
Over there!
不! 不! 那边! 那是我们的人!
No! No! Over there! They're our people!
把 Dalek 的枪卸了!
Cut the Dalek gun off!
不! 啊!...
No! Ah!...
跟你说把他们的枪卸了!
I told you to cut the gun off!
已经切断了啊!
I did!
你杀死了我们自己的人!
You've killed our own people!
我们必须得拆除它们的枪, 只能这样.
We have to dismantle the gun, that's all.
噢, 快看.
Oh, look at it.
你们的-用途-已经-结束.
Your usefulness is over.
快来!
Come on!
快, Val. 快来!
Quick, Val. Come on!
博士, 躲在这里太蠢了!
Doctor, it's stupid to hide in here!
那你想到走廊上去试试运气吗? 谢谢了.
Well, do you fancy your chances outside in the corridor? No thanks.
肯定得有别的什么方法.
The answer must be here somewhere.
嘘!
Ssssh!
啊!...
Ah!...
你们必须绝对安静. 它们知道当前的所有事情, 所有! 它们甚至知道你在想什么.
You must be absolutely quiet. They know everything that's going on.
Everything! They even know what you're thinking.
他们的能量从哪里来的, Lesterson?
Where do they get their power from, Lesterson?
啊, 我试过去切断电源, 但离我太远了. 神奇的生物啊, 你不得不佩服他们.
Ah, I tried to turn the power off. But they were miles ahead of me.
Marvellous creatures. You have to admire them.
但我们要去阻止它们!
But we've got to stop them!
哦, 干这事儿太晚了. 它们是一个新的种族, 明白不.
Oh, it's too late for that. They're the new species, you see.
开始从智人手中接管世界了. 人类终有这一天, 都结束了.
Taking over from homo sapiens. Man's had his day. Finished now.
静电-线路-就快-完成.
The static circuit is nearly complete.
马上-我们-可以-抛弃-正在-使用的-电能.
Soon we can abandon the power we are using.
人类-将要-被-毁灭.
The humans are being exterminated.
你听到了吗? 它们要开始使用它们自己的能量!
Did you hear that? They're going to use their own power!
它们自己铺设的线缆. 我以前用过的方法就没法再用了.
The cables they laid. The trick I tried before won't work anymore.
哦, 如果那个方法不好使, 我们就完蛋了.
Oh, eh, if that's no good now, we're finished.
All we can do is marvel at the creatures who are taking our place.
我们所有能做的, 就是对着这些生物惊叹不已, 眼看着它们取代掉我们.
不!
No!
快!
Come on!
别犯傻 - 快走!
Don't be a fool - come on!
这边可以走，快来
别怕, Polly.
Take it easy, Polly.
我们不能做点什么吗?! 他们在谋杀所有人, 一个接一个!
Can't we do anything?! They're murdering everybody, one by one!
都是你造成的. 一开始你为什么要给它们提供能量?
You've done all this. Why did you give them power in the first place?
哦, 我当时可以控制住的, 你看. 然后 Janley 找了她们的一个人
Well, I could control it, you see. And then Janley got one of her men
- Valmar, 好像是这个名字 - 他安装了一个秘密线缆.
- Valmar, I think it was, yes - and he rigged up a secret cable.
那个线缆直接由基地电厂提供电力.
It's carrying power directly from the colony's supply.
哪儿? 在哪儿, Lesterson?
Where? Where is it, Lesterson?
Valmar 是唯一能回答这个问题的人. 当然 Daleks 也能
Valmar's the only one who can answer that. Or the Daleks of course.
它们知道所有事情, 是的, 你问 Daleks 也可以.
They know everything. Yes, you should ask the Daleks.
那么我们必须找到 Valmar.
Then we must find Valmar.
不! 你留在这里照顾 Polly.
No! You stay here and look after Polly.
我过去（过来，快点！啊----）
I'll go.
你必须舍她而去了, Valmar.
You'll have to leave her now, Valmar.
她并不想你们想的那么坏.
She wasn't as bad as you think.
Valmar! Dalek 的能量供应系统在哪儿?
Valmar! Where is the Dalek power.
趴下, 你们俩!
Get down, both of you!
Valmar! Dalek 的能量供应系统在哪儿?
Valmar! Where is the Dalek power supply?
我们必须阻止它们, Valmar. 她死了! 你做不了什么了!
We've got to stop them, Valmar. She's dead!
There's nothing you can do for her!
主线缆在舱体里面. 但你们做不了什么.
The main cable's inside the capsule.
But there's nothing you can do.
一定有某种方法可以切断能量供应.
There must be some way of cutting off the power.
是什么让你觉得我会那样做? 我们需要一点时间. 我知道了! 找人牵制它们!
What makes you think I want to do that? We need more time.
I know. A diversion.
Bragen 的保安! 我们只能利用他们来让 Daleks 无暇估计我们. 你去找 Bragen.
Bragen's guards. We'll have to use them to keep the Daleks busy.
You go to Bragen.
一分队? 你们的情况如何? 你们还在吗一分队?
Section One? Where's your report? Are you there Section One?
二分队? 二分队? 为什么不回答? 你们能听到吗二分队?
Section Two? Section Two? Why don't they answer?
Can you hear me Section Two?
三分队? 噢, 为什么他们不回话? 我是总督. 为什么他们不回话?
Section Three? Oh, why don't they answer?
I'm their Governor. Why don't they answer?
这里是 Bragen. 我现在同 Daleks 讲话.
This is Bragen speaking. I'm speaking to the Daleks.
Daleks, 听我说, 我是总督. 你们必须为我工作. 不要相信叛乱分子.
Daleks, listen to me. I am the Governor.
You must work for me. Do not trust the rebels.
我会给予你们想要的任何东西. 但请立即放下武器. 这里是总督在讲话.
I will give you whatever you want. But immobilise your guns.
This is the Governor speaking.
他是个蠢蛋, 居然想跟 Daleks 谈条件.
He's nuts, trying to talk to the Daleks.
Lesterson, 这个柜子里面是什么?
Lesterson, what's in that cupboard?
什么也没有, 里面是空的.
Nothing. It's quite empty.
正好, 来吧, Polly, 我们躲在这里面比较安全, 很好.
Well, come on, Polly, we'll be safe in there, love.
你们听到我的话了没, Daleks?! 你们必须服从我的命令!
Do you hear me, Daleks?! You will obey my orders!
没用的, Bragen. Daleks 早就不服从你的命令了.
No use, Bragen. The Daleks have stopped obeying your orders.
啊! 保安!
Ah! Guards!
都死了! Daleks 杀死了他们. 你在内城里还有几个保安小队. 他们到这里要多久?
Dead! The Daleks have killed them. You still have your guard units
in the interior. How long will it take them to get here?
看情况.
That depends.
赶紧啊!
Well, get them!
但他们也会被 Daleks 拦截住.
Well, they will be intercepted by the Daleks.
正是! 这会把它们从这里引开, 给博士去寻找对付它们的机会.
Exactly! It will draw them away from here
and give the Doctor a chance to deal with them.
我拒绝让我的保安们去做牺牲.
I refuse to allow my guards to be sacrificed.
那样的话 Daleks 会把这个基地所有的东西都毁掉.
In that case the Daleks will destroy everything on this colony.
保安. 我是 Bragen. 所有小组马上到首府报告
Guards. This is Bragen speaking.
All units will report immediately to the capital.
注意可能会遭遇造反的 Daleks.
Be prepared to face the rebel Daleks.
好了, 你满意了吧?
There. Are you satisfied?
我期望这能有作用.
I hope it works.
Ben! Polly!
博士, 你听到 Bragen 说的了吗?
Doctor, did you hear what Bragen said?
是的, 我听到了.
Yes, I did.
我只能期望 Daleks 都跑到保安那里去.
Well I only hope the Daleks do go for the guards.
好多 Daleks 刚才出去了.
A lot of the Daleks went out just now.
很好, 因为我们要进去. 快来 Valmar. _.
Good, because we're going inside. Come on Valmar. _.
Ben, 把那根闲置的线缆给我们. Polly, 你负责在门口放哨.
Ben, give us that spare cable over there.
Polly, keep watch at the door.
你知道你在做什么吧?
Well, you know what you're doing?
我当然知道!
Of course I do!
嗯, 为什么你不直接把插头都拔掉, 这样不就都切断了?
Well, why can't you just take all the plugs out and cut the power off?
因为我更喜欢按我的方法来!
Because I prefer to do it my way!
小心!
Look out!
静电-能量-已经-储存. 我们-可以-拆除-人类-电力-系统.
Static power is being stored.
We can dismantle the human electric system.
Daleks-法律-已经-生效
The law of the Daleks is in force.
终结-所有-人类.
Extermination of humans.
我们的-线缆-已被-移动.
Our cables have been moved.
我可以告诉你们是谁干的!
And I could tell you who did it!
你-在-这里-干-什么?
What were you doing in there?
我想帮助你们.
I want to help you.
为什么?
Why?
我-是-你的-仆人.
I am your servant.
我们-不-需要-人类-现在
We do not need humans now.
啊, 这样的话, 你也不应该杀我. 是我给了你们生命.
Ah, then, but you wouldn't kill me. I gave you life.
是的, 你-给了-我们-生命.
Yes, you gave us life.
啊!... 啊!... 啊!... 啊!... 啊!... 啊!...
Ah!... Ah!... Ah!... Ah!... Ah!... Ah!...
还有-两个...
There are two...
终结！啊!... 啊!... 终结！
Exterminate! Ah!... Ah!... Exterminate!
它怎么了?
What happened to it?
我不知道.
I don't know.
看来你的朋友, 那个监察员, 获得了最终胜利.
It seems that your friend, the Examiner, was successful after all.
现在我要恢复这个星球的法律和秩序了.
Now I shall restore law and order on this planet.
不是你的法律, Bragen. 一切已经结束了.
Not your law, Bragen. That's finished for good.
你要服从我, 否则...
You'll obey me, or...
你的日子已经结束了, Bragen. 现在没人再服从你了.
Your day is over, Bragen. No one will obey you now.
我仍然是总督, 而且你将...
I'm still the Governor, and you will...
Valmar.
他是个凶手.
He was a murderer.
流了够多的血了.
Enough of guns.
还有好多收尾的工作要做. 我们一起来重建吧. 损毁的程度怎样?
There's a lot of clearing up to be done.
We will rebuild together. What is the extent of the damage?
哦, 我不知道还能不能修好. 整个电力系统都...
Oh, I don't know if its repairable.
The whole electrical system.
你还好吧?
Are you all right?
哦, 他没事. The clot knocked himself out.
Oh, he's OK. The clot knocked himself out.
这是个奇迹. 你怎么做到的?
It's a miracle. How did you do it?
呃? 发生了什么? 我做了什么? 我做了什么?
Eh? What happened? What did I do? What did I do?
你摧毁了 Daleks, 那就是你做的!
You destroyed the Daleks, that's what you did!
没必要谦虚了.
No need to be modest about it.
是我干的?
Did I do that?
是的, 你知道的!
You know you did!
你用光了基地供电系统的电力 - 让它们过载了 - 炸掉了它们的临时静电电路. 干得不错啊?
You used the power from the colony's electric supply - overfed it
- and blew up their temporary static circuit. Well didn't you?
是我干的吗?
Did I do all that?
你是阻止了 Daleks, 但你就没想到你对这个基地造成的损害吗?
You may have stopped the Daleks,
but have you any idea of the damage you've done to the colony?
哦. There was a blow back, was there?
Oh. There was a blow back, was there?
A blow back? 我们的电力供应被毁掉了! 可能需要数月我们才能让事情回归正常.
A blow back? Our power supply has been destroyed!
It'll be months before we can get things back to normal.
Valmar!
那太不幸了.
That is unfortunate.
但你必须得用这个方法吗?
But did it have to be this way?
我造成了很大的破坏, 是吧?
I did a lot of damage, did I?
得了.
Come on.
我觉得我们还是赶紧离开这里吧, 赶在他们送账单过来之前.
I think we'd better get out of here before they send us the bill.
我并没有期望有一个管弦乐团奏奏乐，但也不觉得一句“谢谢你”会伤害到谁
Well, I mean I didn't expect the brass bands to be playing,
but I wouldn't have thought a 'thank you' would have hurt anybody.
不过 Ben, 想想那些可怜的人 - 全都死了.
But Ben, think of all those poor people - all killed.
我知道, 但是博士救了整个基地, 否则它早就被完全抹平了.
I know, but the Doctor saved the colony from being completely wiped out.
嗯.
Hmmm.
吔, 他不是一直在警告他们, 是他们自己不听啊
Yeah, and he was telling them all along, but would they listen?
他向 Valmar 、Quinn 和所有人解释的时候，也没有显得很有说服力
Mind you, he wasn't very convincing when he was trying to
explain it to Valmar and Quinn and everybody.
嗯, 是不太有,  是吧
No he wasn't, was he?
博士, 你的确知道自己在做什么, 对吧?
Doctor? You did know what you were doing, didn't you?